<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--
  Copyright 2014 Federico Iosue (federico.iosue@gmail.com)
  
  Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
  you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
  You may obtain a copy of the License at
  
    http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0
  
  Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
  distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
  WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
  See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
  limitations under the License.
-->
<changelog bulletedList="true">

    <changelogversion versionName="4.3.2" changeDate="Feb 10, 2014">
        <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Arabic language support (thanks Khalid El Buokhari)</changelogtext>
        <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Google+ multimedia files inclusion. You can use Google Photo app to have access to remotely stored images and save them in ON (even animated)</changelogtext>
        <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Multi-type attachments import. Try to export from Google Keep to ON notes with both images and audio!</changelogtext>
        <changelogtext>Improved performance on note editing and saving</changelogtext>
        <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Checklist misbehaviors on orientation changes and pressing "next" key on the last item</changelogtext>
    </changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="4.3.1" changeDate="Feb 9, 2014">
        <changelogtext>Auto-link recognition is now disabled by default to avoid Samsung keyboard crashes</changelogtext>
        <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Now tags color are shown correctly even in smaller devices and Nexus tablets</changelogtext>
        <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Black sub-settings screen's background on Gingerbread is now white</changelogtext>
        <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Fixed crash when batch deleting notes in list for some devices</changelogtext>
    </changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="4.3.0" changeDate="Feb 8, 2014">
        <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Implemented new tags creation directly from note tagging dialog</changelogtext>
        <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Expanded notifications on Android versions major than Jelly Bean to allow dismissing reminder or delay it</changelogtext> 
        <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Users can now choose to use default Android calendar and time pickers dialog instead of Googleìs ones</changelogtext>
        <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] You can now force the application language from settings</changelogtext>    
        <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] If your location address can't be retrieved due to missing network you'll be informed (location coordinates will be saved in any case)</changelogtext>        
        <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Ukrainian language support (thanks Andriy Poznakhovskyy)</changelogtext>                
    	<changelogtext>Moved attachments thumbnails and location above note content text to emphasize them</changelogtext>       
        <changelogtext>If note title is empty the first line on content will be used instead to keep uniform aspect and optimize space usage</changelogtext>       
        <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Tagging from inside note detail now functions again</changelogtext>
    	<changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] When prompted for update the application will check if Play Store is installed and will not crash anymore</changelogtext>
 	</changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="4.2.1" changeDate="Feb 6, 2014">       
    	<changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Tags dialogs now shows colors and selection happens with just one click</changelogtext>
    	<changelogtext>[b]New![/b] When an app crash happens you'll be informed (for transparency) and you can insert a comment</changelogtext>
    	<changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Resolved multiselection wrong coloration</changelogtext>
    	<changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Resolved many check-list issues</changelogtext>
 	</changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="4.2.0" changeDate="Feb 5, 2014">       
    	<changelogtext>[b]New![/b] [u]A fresh stable version is out!![/u] </changelogtext>
    	<changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Chinese language support (thanks ContactFront from XDA)</changelogtext>
 	</changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="4.2.0 Beta 8" changeDate="Feb 3, 2014">   
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Tags colors have been moved to pastel family for a better looking and can be set to cover not only the small tag markers in notes but also the full note item!</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] More elegant password setting screen. Now, if trying to lock a note without having inserted a security password before, you'll be prompted for it just once.</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Notification ringtone customizable from settings</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] New sharing mode</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Tags creations and deletions are now notified with color contextual dialogs</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Added opacity bar in Sketch and fixed popup position</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Swedish language support (thanks Mattias Lundqvist)</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>Tags are now ordered by name, when name is left blank the tag will stay on tail</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>Updated Turkish translation</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Crash when trying to delete a backup on some devices</changelogtext>   
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Crash when switching to other app while drawing a sketch</changelogtext>      
 	</changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="4.2.0 Beta 7" changeDate="Feb 2, 2014">   
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Actionbar and navigation bar transparency in KitKat</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Reminder date and time picker support for smaller devices</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Spanish language support (thanks Sergio Iglesias)</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Slovak language support (thanks Pyler)</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Something is happened to Mr.Jingles...</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>Note editor screen margins changed to optimize screen usage and to perform more easily touch operations on "location" and "reminder" items</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>Updated Russian language</changelogtext>
 	</changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="4.2.0 Beta 6" changeDate="Feb 1, 2014">   
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Beautiful info messages replaced to standard Android toasts popup</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] When a problem occurs the application will not disturb you anymore and will automatically send the issue report if connection is available</changelogtext>
<!--       <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Default language is choosen depending on system locale but now is possible to change it from settings</changelogtext> -->
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] French language support (thanks Kowalski OmniROM and Adrien Pegon)</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>Updated Dutch and Italian translations</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Deletion of sketch when orientation is changed is avoided forcing portrait mode</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] A couple of crashes when tagging notes are nore resolved</changelogtext>
 	</changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="4.2.0 Beta 5" changeDate="Jan 30, 2014">   
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] More contextualization: now [i]Lock or unlock[/i] and [i]Toggle checklist[/i] items in editor menu changes depending on the note status</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>Many layout modifications</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Lot of fixes thanks to beta testers feedback</changelogtext>
 	</changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="4.2.0 Beta 4" changeDate="Jan 29, 2014">   
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Sorting by reminder date criteria</changelogtext>
 	</changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="4.2.0 Beta 3" changeDate="Jan 29, 2014">       
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Notes can now be sorted by ascending reminder date</changelogtext>     
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] If a note is locked its content is not masked in notes' list</changelogtext>        
      <changelogtext>When a note is going to be tagged and no tags already exist the tag creation window is shown</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Finally resolved bug affecting Samsung keyboard and Flesky that caused app crashing when trying to write title or content on empty field and when double-tapping to select text</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] App crashing from when a new note with new-line only is inserted untile when app data are erased</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Tag color is no more reset to default color when saving it without changes</changelogtext>
 	</changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="4.2.0 Beta 2" changeDate="Jan 28, 2014">       
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Add hand-sketches to your notes!</changelogtext>        
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Automatic updates check will tell you when a new version is out (not applied to Beta releases)</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Revisited settings screen to better keeping usable the growing number of options</changelogtext>      
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Corrected checklist behavior on saving when "keep checked items" and "keep checkmarks" options are not selected and refined deletion icon size and action timings</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Attachments' popup sizes fit now the content</changelogtext>
 	</changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="4.2.0 Beta 1" changeDate="Jan 24, 2014">        
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] You can now easily convert from simple text note to [b]checklist[/b] and vice versa</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] 12-hours mode available</changelogtext>           
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Added ACRA for managing crash reports and send me errors information</changelogtext>       
      <changelogtext>Tag markers layout modified: slightly thicker and now both in notes list or in detail will appear like a vertical-left-border for the container card element</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>German translation updated (thanks to Lycox MB)</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] attachments added when discarding note changes will be correctly removed</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] wrong tag association when just one note without previous tag was selected</changelogtext>
 	</changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="4.1.4" changeDate="Jan 30, 2014">
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Crashes with Samsung or Flesky keyboards</changelogtext>
 	  <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Possible crashes on tags creation</changelogtext>
 	</changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="4.1.3" changeDate="Jan 21, 2014">
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Backup notes with default export name now works</changelogtext>
 	</changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="4.1.2" changeDate="Jan 18, 2014">
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Dutch translation (thanks to Martin Coulon)</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] German translation (thanks to Lycox MB)</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Russian translation (thanks to Abdullah Amir)</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Restored correct animated indicator to open left sliding menu</changelogtext>
 	  <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Crash on locking a newly created note fixed</changelogtext>
 	</changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="4.1.1" changeDate="Jan 16, 2014">
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Portugese (Brazil) translation (thanks to Eduardo Riva)</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>Many bugs resolved thanks to your signalations</changelogtext>
 	</changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="4.1.0" changeDate="Jan 15, 2014">
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Italian translation</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Turkish translation (thanks to ufkeee)</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>Removed archive/unarchive actions when navigation differs from Notes or Archived to avoid mistakes</changelogtext>
	  <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Error on device reboot that caused reminders not restored</changelogtext>
 	</changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="4.1.0 Beta 3" changeDate="Jan 11, 2014">
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Audio attachments now are shown with their name to avoid confusing them</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>Faster app launches thanks to heavy code cleaning</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>Batch tagging notes on list now pre-sets actual tag if just one note is selected</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Playing audio recordings without having stopped the previuos one now works correctly</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Tags colored circle are now displayed also on versions previously than Jelly Bean</changelogtext>
     </changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="4.1.0 Beta 2" changeDate="Jan 10, 2014">
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] More efficient backup management (including deletion and size details)</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>Reduced app installer size</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>The improved Settings section now includes a more verbose description for the various options and an About item containing infos on the opensource project</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>Lot of graphical modifications and UI cleaning: fonts homogeneous, transparencies, screens titles, elements padding reduces to optimize spaces...</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Notes icon indicators are now correctly aligned</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] After searching and editing a note the keyboard will no longer appear if unrequested</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Error on widget positioning and wrong backup restore in Android versions minor than 4.0.0</changelogtext>
    </changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="4.1.0 Beta 1" changeDate="Jan 6, 2014">
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Associate notes with colored [u]tags[/u] to categorize and filter them!</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[b]New![/b] Protect single notes from unauthorized accesses using a security password</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Many other minor issues have been resolved</changelogtext>
	</changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="4.0.1" changeDate="Dec 28, 2013">
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Crash on start with spanish language</changelogtext>
	</changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="4.0.0" changeDate="Dec 27, 2013">
      <changelogtext>Implemented card-like interface for notes list elements</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>Added fading animation to location text</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Notes list scrollbar position</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] High battery consumption</changelogtext>
	</changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="3.9.8beta" changeDate="Dec 23, 2013">
      <changelogtext>[b]New! [/b]Show only notes with reminder from navigation drawer</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>Application size reduced cleaning code and libraries</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Crash on app openinig if coming from stable release</changelogtext>
	</changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="3.9.7beta" changeDate="Dec 22, 2013">
      <changelogtext>Added placeholders for image inside note editor</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Notes list is no more loaded twice on application startup</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Old reminders are no more repeated after reboot</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Crash on exiting note after reminder notification</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Reminder chooser setting wrong time by default</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Minor bugs</changelogtext>
	</changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="3.9.6beta" changeDate="Dec 19, 2013">
      <changelogtext>[b]New! [/b]OmniNotes can now receive also shared videos and audio recordings from other apps</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[b]New! [/b]"Reset All Data" option from settings behavior changed. All application data have been moved to private directory on external memory so you can simply use default system data and cache cleaning</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[b]New! [/b]Backup process completely rewritten. Now it's managed by a service and also attachments will be saved</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[b]New! [/b]Added a setting to limit maximum video size</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>Performances boosted up saving attachments thanks to memory accesses optimizations</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>Much faster note deletion thanks to asynchronous processing (batch deletion too)</changelogtext>      
      <changelogtext>Migrated compatibility library to Google's official AppCompat</changelogtext>      
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] Sharing notes to or receiving shared data from other apps now fills correctly the title field</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] note deleting failure when trying to delete from inside note detail</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] missing attachments deletion</changelogtext>
	</changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="3.9.5beta" changeDate="Dec 17, 2013">
      <changelogtext>[b]New! [/b]Video recording</changelogtext>
	</changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="3.9.4beta" changeDate="Dec 17, 2013">
      <changelogtext>[b]New! [/b]Audio recording and playback</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>Note modification date is not updated if no changes are made</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] crash on application opening happening on many devices</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] image opening with wrong applications (ex. torrent, file manager)</changelogtext>
	</changelogversion>
	
    <changelogversion versionName="3.9.3beta" changeDate="Dec 12, 2013">
      <changelogtext>[b]New! [/b]Widget!!</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[b]New! [/b]Consistency improved by making a copy of attachments, now if original is deleted Omni Notes has its own ones</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>Updated search icon to match the standard one from holo light theme</changelogtext>
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] impossibility to open image attachments in gallery</changelogtext>     
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] slowing down waiting location retrieval, now process is parallelized</changelogtext> 
      <changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] missing refresh of note list after inserting note with heavy images</changelogtext>
	</changelogversion>
	
    <changelogversion versionName="3.9.2beta" changeDate="Dec 10, 2013">
        <changelogtext>[b]New! [/b]Now is possible to share contents from other apps to Omni Notes!</changelogtext>
        <changelogtext>[b]New! [/b]Image attachments are shared too</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>[b]New! [/b]Links recognition in notes content and title activable via option in settings</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>[b]New! [/b]Brand new icon and notification icon</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>[b]New! [/b]Asynchronous note saving and loading makes everithing faster</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>Improved sharing function that includes also image attachments</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>Changed the behavior of deleting action in notes detail: now you have to long-press on item (image, location, reminder) and give confirmation</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>Notes are now saved also if there is no text but just attachments, position or reminder set</changelogtext>		
 		<changelogtext>Added selection color on objects click</changelogtext>
 		<changelogtext>Now sorting by date  is done in descendant order</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] multiple reminder notification misbehavior related to wrong note detail opening</changelogtext>
 		<changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] location insertion error</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] image attachments crop to fill a regular grid</changelogtext>
	</changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="3.9.1beta" changeDate="Nov 29, 2013">
		<changelogtext>[b]New! [/b]Notes geolocation!</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>[b]New! [/b]Replaced standard date and time pickers with the new beautiful one from Android 4.3 ported backward to older devices</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>Moved attachment icon on first position in note detail page</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] reminder bug showind notification with some delay and giving error on notification opening when the note was created first time</changelogtext>
    </changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="3.9.0beta" changeDate="Nov 28, 2013">
		<changelogtext>[b]New! [/b]Attachments to notes using camera or gallery images</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>[b]New! [/b]A remainder can be set to receive notes notifications</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>[b]New! [/b]New icons in notes list showing archived status, attachments and reminders</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>[b]New! [/b]Added changelog screen in preferences</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>[b]New! [/b]Removed language choosing from preferences, system locale will be used automatically instead</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>Layout and keyboard popup revisited with an eye to small screen devices</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>Lot of bugs fixes and improvements</changelogtext>
    </changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="3.2.4" changeDate="Nov 22, 2013">
		<changelogtext>[b]New! [/b]Splashscreen added</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>[b]New! [/b]Totally removed Ads</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] layout for small phones</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>INFO section in settings</changelogtext>
    </changelogversion>
    
    <changelogversion versionName="3.2.3" changeDate="Nov 18, 2013">
		<changelogtext>Bugfixes</changelogtext>
    </changelogversion>
    
    <changelogversion versionName="3.2.1 - 3.2.2" changeDate="Nov 17, 2013">
		<changelogtext>Bugfixed and graphic adjustments</changelogtext>
    </changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="3.2.0" changeDate="Nov 15, 2013">
		<changelogtext>[b]New! [/b]Spanish localization</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>[b]New! [/b]Added animations</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>Notes list more cards-like</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>Performance improvements</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>[u]Fixed[/u] issues when searching</changelogtext>
    </changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="3.1.0" changeDate="Nov 14, 2013">
            <changelogtext>Drastically reduced minimum Android version to 2.2</changelogtext>
    </changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="3.0.0" changeDate="Nov 13, 2013">
		<changelogtext>[b][u]Out of closed BETA![/u][/b]</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>[b]New! [/b]Italian localization</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>[b]New! [/b]Confirmation on batch deleting</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>Totally rewritten to achieve compatibility with tablet format</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>Fix Whatsapp sharing</changelogtext>
    </changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="2.2.0" changeDate="Nov 11, 2013">
        <changelogtext>[b]New! [/b]Note searching</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>[b]New! [/b]New font Roboto Slab</changelogtext>
    </changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="2.1.0" changeDate="Nov 9, 2013">
		<changelogtext>New export and import functions using csv file</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>Settings revisited</changelogtext>
    </changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="2.0.0" changeDate="Nov 8, 2013">
		<changelogtext>New export and import functions using csv file</changelogtext>
		<changelogtext>Settings revisited</changelogtext>
    </changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="1.1.0" changeDate="Nov 6, 2013">
            <changelogtext>Basical functions available: inserting, deleting (batch mode too), sorting with various criteria and notes sharing</changelogtext>
    </changelogversion>

    <changelogversion versionName="1.0.0" changeDate="Nov 6, 2013">
            <changelogtext>Initial commit</changelogtext>
    </changelogversion>

</changelog>
